A Guide to the American Lung Association of Virginia (ALAV) Collection
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
American Lung Association of Virginia (ALAV)Collection, 1907-2004
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
ALAV
The extensive collection consists of 424 boxes, 50 are folio boxes.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The American Lung Association of Virginia (ALAV) donated the organization's papers to the University of Virginia Health Sciences Library in 1990 and 1991, under the auspices of then ALAV Executive Director, Dr. Carl Booberg. Another large donation from the ALAV was made in 2009.
Biographical/Historical Information
The American Lung Association (ALA) is the oldest voluntary public health agency in the United States. The original name of the ALA was the National Association for the Study and Prevention of Tuberculosis (NASPT), formed in 1904 to combat the deadliest disease of the time. The name was changed to the National Tuberculosis Association (NTA) in 1918, and finally, with the decline of TB and the rise of other serious lung diseases, to the American Lung Association (ALA) in 1973. The American Lung Association of Virginia (ALAV) has been similarly renamed since its formation in 1909 as the Virginia Anti-Tuberculosis Association. Today, both the national and state associations are dedicated to the prevention, cure, and control of all lung diseases.
The American Lung Association is perhaps best known as "The Christmas Seal People." Since 1907, the Christmas Seal Campaign has raised many millions of dollars toward the fight against lung disease. In 1915, the NASPT launched the Modern Health Crusade, originally to involve children in the Christmas Seal Campaign. Any child who sold ten or more Seals was given a "Crusader certificate of enrollment" on which was printed a list of health rules such as "keep windows open" and "get a long night's sleep." Children who complied with these standards were "promoted" from squire to knight, then to knight banneret, and finally to knight of the round table. By 1919 there were three million "crusaders" in the United States. Two years later, the National Education Association recommended the adoption of a Crusade-like health education system in every elementary school in the country.
The ALAV Collection contains extensive information on the tuberculosis sanatoriums established in Virginia. When the NASPT formed in 1904, there were approximately one hundred sanatoriums in the United States; by 1910, there were nearly four hundred. One of the many sanatoriums built during this period was the Catawba Sanatorium near Roanoke, the first sanatorium in the state of Virginia. In 1908, Captain William Washington Baker (1844-1927), a member of the Virginia General Assembly, introduced a bill to reorganize the State Board of Health. The "Baker Bill" appropriated $20,000 "for the establishment and maintenance of a suitable sanatorium for consumptives." Baker had lost four of his six children to tuberculosis. For his pioneering efforts, he is justly called "the father of Catawba Sanatorium." Baker was also instrumental in the formation of the Virginia Anti-Tuberculosis Association (now the ALAV) in October 1909.
In 1918, the State Board of Health and the Negro Organization Society founded Piedmont Sanatorium as a rest home for African-Americans. Before its establishment, the only treatment facilities for African- Americans were the Central State Hospital for Mental Diseases and the State Penitentiary. Miss Agnes D. Randolph, Director of the Educational Department of the State Board of Health, requested in 1916 an appropriation from the General Assembly to build the sanatorium and purchase three hundred acres of land near Burkeville. The first building at the site was named in her honor.
Blue Ridge Sanatorium opened in April of 1920. The close proximity of the University of Virginia Medical School was a major factor in the government's selection of the Charlottesville area as the site for the new facility. The State Board of Health and the University agreed that a special course in TB would be developed for third and fourth year medical students, to be taught by the Medical Director of Blue Ridge Sanatorium and his staff. The city of Charlottesville donated $15,000 for the building project and promised free water from the city supply for five years.
An online exhibit created by the Historical Collections and Services staff of The Claude Moore Health Sciences Library at the University of Virginia recounts the origin and early history of the ALA. All of the materials featured in the Web exhibit (http://exhibits.hsl.virginia.edu/alav/) are from the Library's ALAV Collection in Historical Collections and Services.
Scope and Content Information
The ALAV Collection contains personal and official correspondence, financial and legal papers, minute books, organizational and scientific reports, educational publicity, photographs, and artifacts. The ALAV Collection contains exhaustive information on the administrative concerns, educational and fund-raising activities, local level activities and regional offices, and the day-to-day operations of Virginia's key agent in the control and prevention of respiratory diseases. The materials in the ALAV Collection document the growth of the organization, as well as the input of a number of notable Virginians, from the early decades of the twentieth century. The ALAV Collection contains materials of use to researchers interested in medical history, epidemiology, respiratory diseases, and the growth of state and national organizations dedicated to public health.
Contents List
- TUBERCLOSIS ABSTRACTS: A REVIEW FOR PHYSICIANS: WRITTEN BY THE NATIONAL TUBERCULOSIS ASSOCIATION, 1928 - 1932, 1 Booklet (Box-folder 001:001)
- TUBERCULOSIS ABSTRACTS: WRITTEN BY THE NATIONAL TUBERCULOSIS ASSOCIATION, 1933 - 1939, TMs, Booklets (2) (Box-folder 001:002)
- TUBERCULOSIS ABSTRACTS: WRITTEN BY THE NATIONAL TUBERCULOSIS ASSOCIATION, 1940 - 1949, TMs, Booklets (2) (Box-folder 001:003)
- TUBERCULOSIS ABSTRACTS: WRITTEN BY THE NATIONAL TUBERCULOSIS ASSOCIATION, 1950 - 1951, TMs (Box-folder 001:004)
- IS TUBERCULOSIS UNDER CONTROL FROM THE PUBLIC HEALTH VIEWPOINT? BY: L. M. GRAVES, M.D., N.D., TDoc (Box-folder 001:005)
- THE PLACE OF VETERANS PROBLEMS IN TUBERCULOSIS CONTROL BY LEO V. SCHNEIDER, M.D., ND, TDoc (Box-folder 001:006)
- ABSTRACT: NURSING ASPECTS OF TUBERCULOSIS CONTROL BY ELIZABETH FULCHER, N.D., TDoc (Box-folder 001:006)
- THE TUBERCULOSIS DEATH RATE AS A CRITERION OD TUBERCULOSIS CONTROL BY DR. HERBERT R. EDWARDS, N.D., TDoc (Box-folder 001:008)
- TUBERCULOSIS PRGRAMS IN COLLEGES BY VIVIAN V. DRENCKHAHN, N.D., TDoc (Box-folder 001:009)
- TUBERCULOSIS IN MENTAL AND PENAL INSTITUTIONS BY ROBERT E. PLUNCKETT, N.D., TDoc (Box-folder 001:010)
- CHEST X-RAYING IN LARGE GENERAL HOSPITALS BY JOHN M. MC BRYDE, N.D., TDoc (Box-folder 001:011)
  FROM CHARITY HOSPITAL OF LOUISIANA AT NEW ORLEANS
- ABSTRACT: INTERNATIONAL RELATIONSHIP IN REGARD TO TUBERCULOSIS CONTROL, N.D., TDoc (Box-folder 001:012)
- BCG IN TUBERCULOSIS CONTROL BY JOSEPH ANDERSON, M.D., N.D., TDoc (Box-folder 001:013)
- REHABILITATION IN TUBERCULOSIS CONTROL BY PAUL S. BARRETT, N.D., TDoc (Box-folder 001:014)
- ACTION - RSVP - CORRESPONDENCE, 1980 - 1981, TDoc (5) (Box-folder 001:015)
- ACTION - RSVP - GENERAL INFORMATION, 1975 - 1979, TForms, TL (Box-folder 001:016)
- ACTION - RSVP GRANT, 1975 - 1976, TL, TForms (Box-folder 001:017)
- ADDRESSOGRAPH - MULTIGRAPH - ORDER FOR EQUIPMENT, 1959 - 1965, TL, TLS, TForm (Box-folder 001:018)
- AD HOC COMMITTEE ON STATE STRUCTURE, 1974 - 1975, TDocs, TMemo (Box-folder 001:019)
- THE TUBERCULOSIS SITUATION IN VIRGINIA, N.D., TDoc (Box-folder 001:020)
- PRESIDENT'S ADDRESS, February 24 1928, TDoc (Box-folder 001:022)
- A SUGGESTION FOR A STATE CAMPAIGN AGAINST TUBERCULOSIS BY LAWRAWSON BROWN, N.D., TDoc (Box-folder 001:023)
- ADVENTURES IN PREVENTION: THE GIANT KILLER BY ROY K. FLANNAGAN, M.D., February 22 1937, TDoc (Box-folder 001:024)
- THE ETERNAL BATTLE: ANILLUSTRATED STOCK LECTURE INTEDED PRIMARILY FOR USE AMONG SOLDIERS ANS SAILORS OF THE UNITED STATES ARMY AND NAVY BY H.A. PATTISON, M.D., May 1 1918, Booklet (Box-folder 001:025)
  PREPARED BY THE NATIONAL TUBERCULOSIS ASSOCIATION
- ITINERARY AND PROGRAM OF DR. ALGERNON B. JACKSON, 1916 - 1929, TL, TDoc (Box-folder 001:026)
- FOURTH ANNUAL CONFERENCE ON ADULT EDUCATION, 1951, TDoc (Box-folder 001:027)
- ADULT EDUCATION ASSOCIATION OF VIRGINIA, 1952, TDoc (Box-folder 001:028)
- ADULT EDUCATION ASSOCIATION OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, 1954, TLS, Pamphlets (2) (Box-folder 001:029)
- SIXTH ANNUAL CONFERENCE ON ADULT EDUCATION, June 1954, TDoc (Box-folder 001:030)
- ADULT EDUCATION ASSOCIATION, 1957 - 1958, TDoc, Pamphlets (2) (Box-folder 001:031)
- VLA/VTS ADULT LUNG DISEASE COMMITTEE, 1980 - 1981, TDoc (10)TL (3), TMemo (4) (Box-folder 001:014)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1963 - 1964, TL (7), Booklet, TMemo (3), Reprint, Pamphlets (3) (Box-folder 002:001)
- AIRWAYS PERIODICAL, 1979 - 1980, Booklets (2) (Box-folder 002:002)
- AIRWAYS PERIODICAL, 1976 - 1978, Booklets (7) (Box-folder 002:003)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1962 - 1963, TLS (16), Pamphlets (10), TMemo (2) (Box-folder 002:004)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1961 - 1962, TMemo (4), TLS (9), TDoc (5) (Box-folder 002:005)
- AIR POLLUTION SEMINAR - VLA - VACC, 1970 - 1971, TDoc (13), TLS (6), TMemo (3), ALS (1) (Box-folder 002:006)
- ALABAMA TUBERCULOSIS ASSOCIATION: CHANGING TRENDS IN THE CHRISTMAS SEAL SALE, 1951, TDoc (Box-folder 002:007)
- ALTRUSA CLUB; RICHMOND, VIRGINIA, 1956 - 1957, TMemo (8), TDoc (2) (Box-folder 002:008)
- AMERICAN ACADEMY OF GENERAL PRACTICE, 1972 - 1973, TForm (Box-folder 002:009)
- VIRGINIA SOCIETY OF THE AMERICAN ASSOCIATION FOR RESPIRATORY THERAPY SEMINAR IN CHARLOTTESVILLE, April 1970, Pamphlet (Box-folder 002:010)
- AMERICAN ASSOCIATION FOR RESPIRATORY THERAPY, 1974 - 1977, TDoc (6) (Box-folder 002:011)
- AMERICAN ASSOCIATION OF SOCIAL WORKERS, RICHMOND CHAPTER, 1952 - 1954, TDoc (6), Pamphlet (2), TLS (5) (Box-folder 002:012)
- AMERICAN BANK AND TRUST COMPANY, 1932 - 1939, TLS (Box-folder 002:013)
- AMERICAN MEDICAL ASSOCIATION CONTINUING MEDICAL EDUCATION NEWSLETTER, April 1973 - March 1974, TDoc (9) (Box-folder 003:001)
- AMERICAN MEDICAL ASSOCIATION CONTINUING MEDICAL ASSOCIATION NEWSLETTER, April 1974-September 1974, TDoc (8) (Box-folder 003:002)
- AMERICAN MEDICAL ASSOCIATION CONTINUING MEDICAL EDUCATION NEWSLETTER, November 1977 - July 1979, TDoc (9) (Box-folder 003:003)
- AMERICAN MEDICAL ASSOCIATION CONTINUING MEDICAL EDUCATION NEWSLETTER, August 1979-February 1981, TDoc (19) (Box-folder 003:004)
- AMERICAN MEDICAL ASSOCIATION CONTINUING MEDICAL EDUCATION FACT SHEET, 1979 - 1981, TDoc (4), Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 003:005)
- LOCAL TUBERCULOSIS ASSOCIATIONS: CORRESPONDENCE, 1916 - 1948, TMemo (14), TLS (5), TDoc (11) (Box-folder 003:006)
- ADVERTISING CAMPAIGN, C. 1940, Flyers (2), Pamphlets (3), 8x10 B&W photo (2) (Box-folder 003:007)
- VTA REHABILITATION ADVISORY COMMITTEE, 1924 - 1950, TDoc (10), TLS (36) (Box-folder 003:008)
- REHABILITATION ADVISORY COMMITTEE, 1951 - 1953, TDoc (18), TMemo (1), TLS (3), Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 003:009)
- OTHER STATE TUBERCULOSIS ASSOCIATIONS, 1948, TMs (Box-folder 003:010)
- OTHER STATE TUBERCULOSIS ASSOCIATIONS, 1948 - 1950, TMs (Box-folder 003:011)
- TESTIMONY IN DEFENSE OF THE CLEAN AIR ACT, June 11, 1974, TDoc (Box-folder 004:001)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1974 - 1975, TMemo (3), TLS, TDoc (2) (Box-folder 004:002)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1975 - 1976, TLS (1), TDoc (4), Pamphlet (4), TMemo (1) (Box-folder 004:003)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1976 - 1977, TLS (4), TDoc (2), Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 004:004)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1977 - 1978, TDoc (3), Pamphlet (2) (Box-folder 004:005)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1978 - 1979, TLS (8), TDoc (2), TMemo (2), Pamphlet (4) (Box-folder 004:006)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1979 - 1980, TLS (4), TDoc (6), TMemo (3) (Box-folder 004:007)
- AIR CONSERVATION COMMITTEE, 1980 - 1981, TMemo (1), TM (3), Pamphlet (6) (Box-folder 004:008)
- AIR CONSERVATION COMMITTEE, 1973 - 1974, TM (Box-folder 004:009)
- AIR CONSERVATION COMMITTEE, 1976 - 1977, Pamphlet 6), TM (3), TLS (Box-folder 004:010)
- AIR CONSERVATION COMMITTEE, 1977 - 1978, TMemo (2), TM (Box-folder 004:011)
- AIR CONSERVATION COMMITTEE, 1978 - 1979, TM (Box-folder 004:012)
- AIR CONSERVATION COMMITTEE, 1979 - 1980, TM (3) (Box-folder 004:013)
- VLA: AIR CONSERVATION COMMITTEE, N. D., TM (Box-folder 004:014)
- REPORT: CITY OF COVINGTON, VIRGINIA AIR POLLUTION STUDY, 1959, TDoc (1), Map (1) (Box-folder 005:001)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1964 - 1965, Reprint (3), TMemo (9), TLS (7), TDoc (7), Invitation (Box-folder 005:002)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1965 - 1966, TLS (5), Booklet (4), Pamphlet (3) (Box-folder 005:003)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1966 - 1967, TDoc (16), TLS (10), TMemo (2) (Box-folder 005:004)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1968 - 1969, Pamphlet (6), TLS (12), TMemo (5), TDoc (12) (Box-folder 005:006)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1969 - 1970, TLS (16), TMemo (2), TDoc (6), Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 005:007)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1970 - 1971, TMemo (6), Pamphlet (13), TLS (12), TDoc (11) (Box-folder 005:008)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1971 - 1972, Pamphlet (6), TDoc (12), TLS (9), TMemo (2) (Box-folder 005:00919)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1972 - 1973, Pamphlet (2), TLS, TDoc (3) (Box-folder 005:010)
- AIR POLLUTION CONTROL PROGRAM, 1973 - 1974, Pamphlet (1), TMemo (2), TDoc (1) (Box-folder 005:011)
- ALAV COLLECTION: PROCESSING SCOPE AND CONTENT, February 1, 1991, TDoc (4) (Box-folder 006:001)
- AMERICAN PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATION, 1949, Booklet (3), TDoc (1) (Box-folder 006:002)
- AMERICAN PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATION, 1922 - 1952, TLS (7), Booklet (2) (Box-folder 006:003)
- AMERICAN PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATION, 1971 - 1972, TMemo (1), TForm (1), Booklet (1) (Box-folder 006:004)
- AMERICAN PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATION, 1973 - 1974, TMemo (Box-folder 006:005)
- AMERICAN PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATION, 1975 - 1976, TDoc (1), TLS (1), Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 006:006)
- AMERICAN PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATION, 1976 - 1977, TLS (1), Booklet (1), TDoc (4) (Box-folder 006:007)
- AMERICAN PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATION, 1978 - 1979, TLS (2), Pamphlet (1), TDoc (11), TMemo (1), TForm (1) (Box-folder 006:008)
- NATIONAL CONFERENCE ON AIR POLLUTION: ATTENDANCE LIST, December 1966, Booklet (1) (Box-folder 006:009)
- MEMBERSHIP OF THE NATIONAL AIR CONSERVATION COMMISSION, January 23, 1967, Booklet (1) (Box-folder 006:010)
- AIR POLLUTION: REPORT TO THE VIRGINIA ADVISORY LEGISLATIVE COUCIL, 1965, Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 006:011)
- SCIENCE SEES POOR HEALTH TIED TO BAD AIR, March 25, 1966, Reprint (1) (Box-folder 006:012)
- MAINTAINING THE EFFECTIVENESS OF ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS BY VERNON G. MACKENZIE, May 5, 1966, Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 006:013)
  U. S. DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH
- AUTOMOTIVE AIR POLLUTION, March 25, 1966, Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 006:014)
  CLEAN AIR ACT
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY: MINUTES AND REPORTS OF THE COMMITTEE ON MEDICAL RESEARCH, October 1953, TDoc (Box-folder 007:001)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY: REPORTS AND MINUTES OF MEETINGS OF THE COMMITTEE ON MEDCAL RESEARCH, May 1954 - July 1954, TDoc (1), TMemo (1) (Box-folder 007:002)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY, 1954 - 1955, TLS (12), TDoc (7), TMemo (1), Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 007:003)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY, 1955 - 1956, TLS (2), TDoc (6) (Box-folder 007:004)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY, 1956 - 1957, TDoc (9), TLS (23), Pamphlet (2) (Box-folder 007:005)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY, 1957 - 1958, TLS (15), TDoc (4) (Box-folder 007:006)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY: MINUTES OF COUNCIL MEETING, May 1954, TDoc (1) (Box-folder 007:007)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY: REPORTS AND MINUTES OF THE MEDICAL RESEARCH MEETINGS, 1954 - 1955, TDoc (12), TMemo (1) (Box-folder 007:008)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY: COMMITTEE ON MEDICAL EDUCATION, 1953 - 1954, TLS (2), TDoc (3) (Box-folder 007:008)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY, 1958 - 1959, TLS (12), TDoc (8), TMemo (3), Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 007:009)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY: MINUTES OF COUNCIL MEETING & COMMITTEE MEETINGS, May 1958, TDoc (Box-folder 007:009)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY, 1959 - 1960, TLS (16), TMemo (1), Pamphlet (2), TDoc (7) (Box-folder 007:010)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY: MINUTES OF COUNCIL MEETING AND COMMITTEE REPORTS, May 1959, TDoc (Box-folder 007:011)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY, 1952 - 1953, TDoc (11), TLS (6), Pamphlet (1), TMemo (2) (Box-folder 008:001)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY: REPORT TO THE COMMITTEE ON MEDICAL RESEARCH, May 1952, TDoc (3) (Box-folder 008:002)
- CONSTITUTION OF THE AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY, 1952, TDoc (14) (Box-folder 008:003)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY, 1951 - 1952, TDoc (6), TLS (1), TMemo (1) (Box-folder 008:004)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY: VIRGINIA CHAPTER, 1952, TDoc, TMemo (Box-folder 008:005)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY: MINUTES OF THE COMMITTEE ON MEDICAL RESEARCH, October 1951, TDoc (5) (Box-folder 008:006)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY: COMMITTEE ON MEDICAL EDUCATION, 1952 - 1953, TLS (1), TDoc (5) (Box-folder 008:007)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY, April 1953 - July 1954, TLS (2), TDoc (15), TMemo (1) (Box-folder 008:008)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY, May 1953, TDoc (1) (Box-folder 008:009)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY: MINUTES OF THE ATS MEETING, 1953 - 1954, TDoc (2), TMemo (1) (Box-folder 008:010)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY, August 1953 - March 1954, Pamphlet (1), TDoc (15), TLS (14), TMemo (3) (Box-folder 008:011)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1968, TDoc (12), TLS (5), TMemo (4) (Box-folder 009:001)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1969, TDoc (3), Pamphlet (2), TLS (3), TMemo (5) (Box-folder 009:002)
- CLINICAL NOTES ON RESPIRATORY DISEASES, 1968 - 1969, Journals (2) (Box-folder 009:003)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY: SPECIAL MEETING IN HOUSTON, TEXAS, May 18-22, 1968, TDoc (15), Pamphlets (2) (Box-folder 009:004)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY: A RESOLUTION ON RESEARCH AND EDUCATION FUNDS, May 19, 1968, Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 009:005)
- NATIONAL TUBERCULOSIS AND RESPIRATORY DISEASE ASSOCIATION REPORT OF THE COMMITTEE TO STUDY RESEARCH AND MEDICAL EDUCATION PROGRAMS, May 24, 1968, Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 009:006)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY BYLAWS, 1968, Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 009:007)
- NTRDA AD HOC COMMITTEE TO STUDY RESEARCH AND MEDICAL EDUCATION PROGRAMS, May 24, 1968, TDoc (1) (Box-folder 009:008)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY: MINUTES OF EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE MEETING, May 22, 1968, TDoc (1) (Box-folder 009:009)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY DIRECTORY 1960-1961, 1960 - 1961, TDoc (Box-folder 009:010)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY: MINUTES OF THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE MEETING, Ferbuary 5, 1961, TDoc (Box-folder 009:011)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY: MINUTES OF THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE MEETING, Ferbuary 7-8, 1960, TDoc (Box-folder 009:012)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1960 - 1961, TLS (4), TDoc (6) (Box-folder 009:013)
- AMERICAN TRUDEAU SOCIETY OFFICIAL DIRECTORY, July 1, 1959, Booklet (Box-folder 009:014)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY ORGANIZATION AND COMMITTEE STRUCTURE, 1961 - 1962, TDoc (Box-folder 009:015)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1961 - 1962, TMemo (1), TDoc (16), TLS (16) (Box-folder 009:016)
- AMERICAN (VIRGINIA) THORACIC SOCIETY CONSTITUTION, 1961 - 1962, TDoc (Box-folder 009:017)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY DIRECTORY 1961- 1962, 1961 - 1962, TDoc (Box-folder 009:018)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY: MINUTES OF THE COUNCIL MEETING IN CINCINNATI, OHIO, May 20 - 21, 1961, TDoc (2) (Box-folder 009:019)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY MEDICAL SECTION OF THE NTA, 1960 - 1961, TDoc (1) (Box-folder 009:020)
- COMMITTEE FOR APPRAISAL OF PROGRAMS AND FINANCES OF TB ASSOCIATIONS TO THE NT BOARD OF DIRECTORS, May 25 - 26, 1961, TDoc (Box-folder 009:021)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1962 - 1963, TLS (17), TDoc (17), TMemo (4) (Box-folder 009:022)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY: DIRECTORY OF COMMITTEESS AND CHARGES, 1975 - 1976, Booklet (1) (Box-folder 010:001)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY: REPORT OF THE TASK FORCE ON COMPREHENSIVE CARE FOR PATIENTS WITH COPD, 1975, Booklet (1) (Box-folder 010:002)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY: PULMONARY TERMS AND SYMBOLS, 1974, Booklet (1) (Box-folder 010:003)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY: TRAINING PROGRAMS IN RESPIRATORY DISEASE, 1979, Booklet (Box-folder 010:004)
- HISTORY OF THE AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1979, Booklet (1) (Box-folder 010:005)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1974 - 1975, TDoc (4), TMemo (2), TLS (1), Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 010:006)
- AMERICAN THORACIC ASSOCIATION GUIDELINES FOR THE TREATMENT OF PULMONARY DISEASE, 1973, Booklet (1) (Box-folder 010:007)
- TUBERCULOSIS STATISTICS: STATES AND CITIES, 1973, Booklet (Box-folder 010:008)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1973 - 1974, TDoc (3), TLS (4) (Box-folder 010:009)
- AMERICAN THORACIC ASSOCIATION: THE PHYSICIANS VIEW OF THE AMERICAN LUNG ASSOCIATION, August 1973, TMemo (1), TDoc (1), Pamphlet (1) (Box-folder 010:010)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY: MINUTES OF THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE MEETING, May 1973, TDoc (1) (Box-folder 010:011)
- AMERICAN THORACIC ASSOCIATION EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE MEETING MINUTES, November 1973, TDoc (1) (Box-folder 010:012)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY GUIDELINES FOR TUBERCULOSIS ASSOCIATIONS APPLYING FOR GRANTS, 1973, TDoc (1) (Box-folder 010:013)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY MEMBERSHIP AND FELLOWSHIP APPLICATIONS, 1973, TDoc (4) (Box-folder 010:014)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1972 - 1973, TDoc (9), TLS (5), TMemo (5) (Box-folder 010:015)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY MINUTES OF THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE MEETING, March 1972, TDoc (1) (Box-folder 010:016)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY COMMITTEE STRUCTURE AND COMMITTEE RESPONSOBILITIES, 1972 - 1973, TDoc (1) (Box-folder 010:017)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1971 - 1972, TDoc (13), TMemo (5), TLS (3) (Box-folder 010:018)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY HISTOPLASMINE (TB) TEST, 1973, B&W Photo (1), TDoc (1), Booklet (1) (Box-folder 010:019)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY TRAINING PROGRAMS IN RESPIRATORY DISEASE, 1970, Booklet (Box-folder 010:020)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY ANUAL MEETING SCIENTIFIC ABSTRACTS, May 21 - 24, 1972, Booklet (Box-folder 010:021)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY: SIX LUNG ASSOCIATION PROGRAM SUGGESTIONS, 1973, Booklet (Box-folder 010:022)
- AMERICAN THORACIC ASSOCIATION MINUTES OF THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE MEETING, November 6 - 7, 1970, TDoc (1) (Box-folder 010:023)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1970 - 1971, TDoc (10), TLS (14), TMemo (1) (Box-folder 010:024)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1971, TDoc (1) (Box-folder 010:025)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1969 - 1970, TLS (7), TDoc (4), TMemo (6) (Box-folder 010:026)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY: ANNUAL MEETING MEDICAL ABSTRACTS, May 1969, Pamphlets (2) (Box-folder 010:027)
- AMERICAN COLLEGE OF CHEST PHYSICIANS 46TH ANNUAL SCIENTIFIC ASSEMBLY PROGRAM, October 1980, Booklet (Box-folder 011:001)
- THE 55 TRUDEAU MEDALISTS (1926 - 1980) BY FRED AYVAZIAN, M. D., 1980, TDoc (Box-folder 011:002)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1979 - 1981, TLS (10), TDoc (12), TMemo (14) (Box-folder 011:003)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY DIRECTORY OF COMMITTEE AND CHARGES, 1980 - 1981, Booklet (Box-folder 011:004)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY BYLAWS, October 1980, TDoc (Box-folder 011:005)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1978 - 1979, TDoc (11), TLS (7), TMemo 96), Pamphlet (2) (Box-folder 011:006)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY COUNCIL MEETING, May 1980, TDoc (1), TMemo (1) (Box-folder 011:007)
- AMERICAN THORACIC SOCIETY, 1977 - 1978, TLS (1), TDoc (20, TMemo (1), Pamphlet (3) (Box-folder 011:008)